Intelligence is rate of learning. It's speed. It's a measurement of speed. So it means how many times
do you need to be exposed to the same condition in order to change your behavior? If I teach
someone something, that's script. And then on the first try, they say DEF. And someone else,
it takes five tries for them to say DEF. They are not as intelligent as the first person.
Here's why this is interesting. Every person who's listening to this right now has listened to a
thousand fucking podcasts, and they're in the exact same condition, and yet they have not changed
their behavior, which means one, they have not learned, and two, they are dumb. Which also means
that if you can control your behavior, you can also control how intelligent you are. And so if
you want to be a smart cookie, then it means that you just decrease the amount of times that you do
not change your behavior under the same conditions. Every time you watch or you consume a piece of
content and you read a book, if you think, what behavior am I going to change as a result of
this? If the answer is nothing, you wasted your time and you pretended to be learning,
but you were really entertaining yourself.